Alright, well, it's five after,
好的，已经五点了，
so I'll just go ahead started.
所以我就开始了。
So today's lecture is the Q&A on the first lab,
所以今天的课程是第一个实验的问答，
the MapReduce lab,
MapReduce 实验，
and also some just general coding Q&As for Go programming,
还有一些关于 Go 编程的通用编码问答，
that might help in future labs.
可能会对未来的实验有所帮助。
So feel free to stop at any time
所以你可以随时停下来，
or put questions in the chat,
或者在聊天中提出问题，
and I'll be checking it occasionally,
我会偶尔检查一下，
and I'm sure like other [] can also help as well,
我相信其他[]也能提供帮助，
if you are unmuted and typing,
如果你未静音并且正在打字，
it would be helpful if you muted,
如果你静音，会很有帮助，
but yeah.
不过，是的。
Alright, so the agenda for today,
好的，那么今天的议程，
the first thing I'm going to do is,
我要做的第一件事是，
actually walk through a solution of lab 1,
演示实验 1 的解决方案，
and this is my personal solution,
这是我个人的解决方案，
it's probably not perfect,
它可能并不完美，
but it's an example of what you could have done,
但这是你可以做的一个例子，
second, we're going to discuss some alternative solution designs,
第二，我们将讨论一些替代的解决方案设计，
someone is still typing.
还有人在打字。
[], stop typing.
[]，停止打字。
Alright, it's helpful to, [],
好的，很有帮助，
third, we're going to discuss some of the common design mistakes and some of the bugs,
第三，我们将讨论一些常见的设计错误和一些 bug ，
that you guys had in your solutions,
在你们的解决方案中，
four, just over some general tips,
第四，一些一般性的提示，
and then finally we're going to, if there's time, go to some Q&As,
最后，如果有时间，我们会进行一些问答，
both questions you might have right now
你现在可能会有的问题，
and also questions that you submitted before lecture.
还有你在讲课前提交的问题。
So first for the lab solution walkthrough,
所以，首先是实验解决方案演示，
let me know if the fonts too small,
如果字体太小，请告诉我，
I'll just stick with this.
我还是放在这里。
Alright, so I basically, one step by step,
好的，所以我基本上一步一步地，
and I'll show how I developed my solution.
我将展示我是如何开发我的解决方案的。
So the first thing I did was,
所以我做的第一件事是，
this is rpc.go,
这是 rpc.go ，
and the first thing I did was figure out the API,
我做的第一件事就是弄清楚 API ，
in which I wanted my worker and coordinator to communicate,
我想让 worker 和 coordinator 进行交流，
and so the first thing I did was define what types of tasks there are,
所以我做的第一件事就是定义有哪些类型的任务，
and so there Map and Reduce tasks,
所以这里有 Map 和 Reduce 任务，
and in order to signal that,
并且为了表示，
the coordinator has, things the is done, is the Done task,
coordinator 任务已完成，是 Done 任务，
and so, these are the types of task.
所以，这些都是任务的类型。
Zoom in a bit, can you zoom in a bit, the files?
你能放大一点吗，这个文件？
Yeah, is that okay?
好的，这样可以吗？
Yeah, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
Cool, yeah, it's hard for me to tell how it looked,
酷，是的，我很难确定它看起来是什么样子，
yeah, so I hopefully this is good.
好的，我希望这是好的。
And so the there two RPCs I decided to implement,
所以，我决定实现这两个 RPC ，
the first is a worker asking the coordinator to give it a task,
第一个是 worker 请求 coordinator 给它一个任务，
so one of Map Reduce or Done in please exit,
Map Reduce 中的一个或 Done 用来退出，
and basically there's like the argument,
基本上就是这些参数，
you know don't really have any arguments or just asking for a task,
并没有参数，只是请求一个任务，
and the coordinator replies with what task is this,
coordinator 回答这是什么任务，
which task of that type should you do,
你应该做哪种类型的任务，
and also some extra data that's needed for the Map or Reduce tasks,
还有一些 Map 或 Reduce 任务需要的额外数据，
such as the number of Map tasks in the system
例如系统中 Map 任务的数量，
or the number of Reduce tasks.
或者 Reduce 任务的数量。
And the second RPC is a finished task RPC,
第二个 RPC 是完成任务的 RPC ，
that the worker uses to notify the coordinator,
worker 用它来通知 coordinator ，
that it has finished the task,
它已经完成了任务，
and it passes as arguments which task has finished,
它将哪项任务已完成作为参数传递，
and they don't actually really need to get a reply for this.
它们并不需要得到回复。
So that's the first step of the implementation,
所以这是实现的第一步，
so [].
所以。
Alright, so as a second step,
好的，作为第二步，
what I did is implement the handlers for all these RPCs,
我所做的是为所有这些 RPC 实现处理程序，
and so that's in coordinator,
所以这在 coordinator 中，
so, first I had to actually populate the coordinator with the coordinator state
因此，首先我必须用 coordinator 状态填充 coordinator ，
and so there's the Mutex, which protects the state from concurrent access,
这里有一个 Mutex 保护状态的并发访问，
because the coordinator will have multiple threads running concurrently,
因为 coordinator 将有多个并发运行的线程，
then the second part is to keep track of just like the files that we need for Map task,
第二部分是跟踪我们在 Map 任务所需要的文件，
and the number of Map and Reduce tasks,
以及 Map 和 Reduce 任务的数量，
and this metadata is used to track which tasks have we issued,
这些元数据被用来跟踪我们发出了哪些任务，
and which tasks have finished,
以及哪些任务已经完成，
the once that we've issued, we keep track of the timestamps,
一旦我们发布，我们会跟踪时间戳，
that we know if these tasks haven't completed within a certain amount of time,
我们知道如果这些任务没有在一定的时间内完成，
to reissue them,
就重新发布它们，
and finally we have the, like has all,
最后，我们有，有所有的，
has a coordinator finished boolean.
有一个 coordinator 完成的布尔值。
So to handle the GetTask RPC, we have a handler,
所以，为了处理 GetTask RPC ，我们有一个处理程序，
that essentially what it does is,
从本质上讲，它所做的是，
it will set the reply fields,
它会设置 reply 字段，
right now, I haven't yet implemented the part, that actually issues the task,
现在，我还没有实现发布任务的部分，
and if all the Map and Reduce tasks are done,
如果所有的 Map 和 Reduce 任务都完成了，
it will send a Done task to the worker and exit.
它将发送一个 Done 任务给 worker 并退出。
And then we have the the handler for the FinishedTask RPC,
然后我们有 FinishedTask RPC 的处理程序，
and what this does is,
这个所做的是，
it basically depending on what task it was,
它取决于是什么任务，
set that flag to true,
将那个标志设置为 true ，
that has that task has finished.
那个任务已经完成。
So that's the second step,
这就是第二步，
which is implementing the handlers with RPCs.
实现 RPC 的处理程序。
So the third step I have is actually sending the RPCs,
所以，我的第三步是发送 RPC ，
and so that happened is the work here.
就是这里的工作。
So, top of this is,
所以，这个最上面，
we provided what it does is,
我们提供的是，
it starts up this loop,
它启动这个循环，
that basically for every loop,
在每个循环中，
it calls the handler for GetTask in the coordinator,
它调用在 coordinator 中 GetTask 的处理程序，
and depending on what task it gets,
根据它获得的任务的不同，
it will either perform Map task with the relevant data
它将使用相关数据执行 Map 任务，
or metadata that needs perform the Reduce task,
或需要执行 Reduce 任务的元数据，
or in the case of done, it will exit.
或者在 Done 的情况下，它将退出。
And so it's very simple,
所以这很简单，
and once it's finished that task,
一旦它完成了这项任务，
it will send a FinishedTask RPC to the coordinator.
它将发送一个 FinishedTask RPC 给 coordinator 。
So this is just the skeleton code for the worker sending RPCs.
所以，这只是 worker 发送 RPC 的框架代码。
Alright, so we have RPCs, we have handlers, we have the senders,
好的，我们有 RPC ，我们有处理程序，我们有发送者，
and so now, let's actually implement some stuff.
所以现在，让我们来实现一些东西。
So in step four,
所以在第四步中，
it's I just added a ton of handlers to manage this intermediate file,
我只是添加了大量的处理程序来管理这个中间文件，
which a lot of you also did,
你们中的许多人也这样做了，
and basically it uses like os.Rename,
基本上它使用了比如 os.Rename ，
it gets a temporary file,
它会得到一个临时文件，
so it's not too interesting,
所以这并不太有趣，
and then the next step,
然后，下一步，
let's actually implement some of the worker functionality.
让我们实现一些 worker 的功能。
So, we're back in the worker,
所以，我们又回到了 worker ，
and now let's implement the performMap function,
现在让我们实现 PerformMap 函数，
and what this does is, as many you have to do is
这样做的目的是，你们中许多已经做的是，
read the file, map them to keys,
读取文件，将它们映射到键上，
and then create temporary files, write them to the intermediate files,
然后创建临时文件，将它们写入中间文件，
and then we use an atomic rename
然后我们使用原子重命名，
to ensure that maps aren't conflicting
以确保映射不会冲突
as they process the keys and write them.
在处理键和写入键时。
So this is pretty much taken from the sequential implementation
所以这在很大程度上是从顺序实现中提取出来的，
and how you would apply the Map function.
以及如何应用 Map 函数。
And then similarly, we implement the Reduce function,
然后，类似地，我们实现 Reduce 函数，
so here's a performMap,
这里有一个 performMap ，
and then we have performReduce,
然后我们有一个 performReduce ，
and so what that does is,
所以它所做的就是，
it gets all the intermediate files with the appropriate,
它会获取所有中间文件，
from all the Map tasks, for this Reduce tasks,
从所有 Map 任务，到这个 Reduce 任务，
and sorts them, so sorting happens in the, in the worker,
并对它们进行排序，排序发生在 worker 上，
because the worker needs,
因为 worker 需要，
the reducer needs access to all keys of that type,
reducer 需要访问这个类型的所有键，
and then to sort them.
然后对它们进行排序。
It wouldn't make sense for the mapper,
对于 mapper 是没有意义的，
just sort them before,
在之前对它们进行排序，
because the mapper only has access some the keys.
因为 mapper 只访问一些键。
And then we apply the reduce function to all values of the same key,
然后我们对同一个键的所有值应用 reduce 函数，
and then we atomically rename the temporary reduce file to the final reduce file.
然后，我们将临时 reduce 文件原子重命名为最终的 reduce 文件。
So, now this loop we've implemented basically,
所以，现在我们实现的这个循环，
the actual perform the task,
执行任务，
and we're basically done with the worker implementation.
我们基本上完成了 worker 的实现。
So one last step remains,
所以还剩下最后一步，
and that's actually implementing,
这是实现，
how this coordinator tells the worker which tasks to do,
coordinator 如何告诉 worker 要做哪些任务，
and this is probably
这可能是，
where you ran into the most complexity with synchronization in the coordinator.
你在 coordinator 中遇到的最复杂的同步问题。
So, go back to the coordinator,
所以，回到 coordinator ，
so nothing has changed in the state,
所以这个状态什么都没有改变，
so, but now what we've done is,
但现在我们所做的是，
we've added a loop in the coordinator,
我们在 coordinate 中添加了一个循环，
that handles sending the task to the worker.
它负责将任务发送给 worker 。
And when we're issuing the Map task,
当我们发布 Map 任务时，
so first we want to issue all the Map task,
所以首先我们想要发布所有的 Map 任务，
and so essentially what this loop does here is,
基本上这个循环在这里所做的是，
until there's a task to issue,
在有任务要发布之前，
the coordinator will just iterate to this loop,
coordinator 只是迭代这个循环，
and if we're done with all the Map tasks,
如果我们完成了所有的 Map 任务，
that will break out the loop,
这将打破这个循环，
and then, if all the Map tasks are done,
然后，如果所有 Map 任务都完成了，
then we issue Reduce task,
然后我们发布 Reduce 任务，
which is what's in here.
就是这里的东西。
So, yeah, I have, I guess I have one last step,
所以，是的，我想我还有最后一步，
which is actually what we do,
就是我们所做的，
when the maps or reduces, when there's no task to issue
当 maps 或 reduces ，当没有任务要发布时，
and so we want to do then,
所以我们想做的是，
is the coordinator should just wait for a task issue,
coordinator 应该等待任务发布，
and once it, there's a task issue,
一旦发生，就会出现任务发布，
or to another issue iteration the loop
或者到另一个发布循环的迭代，
and then actually issue the task.
然后发布任务。
I'll continue until all the Map were all Reduce tasks are done,
我将继续，直到所有的 Map 或 Reduce 任务完成，
and after done, I'll return again,
完成后，我会再回来，
so let me go to.
所以让我去。
Right, so in order to support that waiting,
所以为了支持那个等待，
what my solution does is it uses a condition variable,
我的解决方案是使用条件变量，
and essentially what that does is,
从本质上讲，它所做的是，
if there are no Map task issue,
如果没有 Map 任务发布，
but the mappers, but there,
但是 mappers ，但是这里，
because we've assigned all of them, for example,
因为我们已经分配了它们所有，
and we're waiting for them,
我们在们它们，
and they haven't timed out yet,
它们还没有超时，
then we want to do is wait,
那么我们要做的就是等待，
because we cannot issue a Reduce task,
因为我们不能发布 Reduce 任务，
if all the mappers have not finished,
如果所有的 mappers 都没有完成，
so we're just going to wait here,
所以我们就在这里等着，
and then once we get some type of signal,
一旦我们收到某种信号，
we're just going to go back to the top of this loop,
我们回到这个循环的顶端，
and check whether we can issue a task again.
检查我们是否可以再次发布任务。
Similarly, if all the reducers aren't done,
同样，如果所有 reducers 都没有完成，
but we can't actually issue the worker a task,
我们不能给 worker 发布任务，
we're going to wait for there to be some type of signals,
我们要等待出现某种信号，
so when does the signal actually happen?
那么信号到底是什么时候出现？
Well, we want to signal any time
好的，我们想要在任何时候发出信号，
either a task has done or for too long and we haven't heard back,
无论任务完成或时间太长，我们没有收到回复，
so there might have been a failure,
所以可能会有失败，
or if the, if a worker has actually completed a task,
或者如果一个 worker 完成了一项任务，
because for example that might mean all the Map tasks has finished,
因为这可能意味着所有 Map 任务都已经完成，
we can move on to a Reduce task.
我们可以继续执行一项 Reduce 任务。
So in order to do that,
所以，为了做到这一点，
what we have are,
我们有的是，
we have a goroutine here,
我们这里有一个 goroutine ，
that's kind of spawn off immediately as the coordinator starts,
这是当 coordinator 开始时发出的，
and what this does is every once in awhile,
它所做的是每隔一段时间，
after some you know maybe every second or so,
在一些或许每秒，
when a task might have finished,
当一项任务可能已经完成时，
or maybe this is ten seconds, I can't remeber,
或许这是十秒，我记不清了，
actually it doesn't really matter,
事实上，这并不重要，
it just wants to wake up the coordinator every so often,
它只是时不时地唤醒 coordinator ，
so the coordinator will do another check
所以 coordinator 会再做一次检查，
to see whether there is a task to issue,
查看是否有要发布的任务，
and so it just loops around,
所以它就这样循环着，
and every second it will broadcast to wake up the coordinator.
每一秒它都会广播唤醒 coordinator 。
And the other time we want to signal when a task is finished,
另一个我们想要在任务完成时发出信号，
so that's actually going to happen in this HandleFinishedTask,
所以，这将在这个 HandleFinishedTask 中发生，
which is called when a worker like [] FinishedTask task RPC,
当一个 worker FinishedTask 任务 RPC 完成时，
and so here we have a Broadcast
所以，在这里有一个 Broadcast ，
right after we set the [] to done or to complete it to done,
在我们将[]设置为 Done 之后，
and when the coordinator goes back to go check one of these loops,
当 coordinator 回去检查其中一个循环时，
and see whether there's a task to finish,
看看有没有任务要完成，
it will see that updated Done status.
它将看到更新后 Done 状态。
So that's essentially my solution,
所以这就是我的解决方案，
it uses cond vars and Mutex to protect shared state of coordinator.
它使用条件变量和 Mutex 来保护 coordinator 的共享状态。
So this is only one possible solution
所以这只是一种可能的解决方案，
and I'll get back to here,
然后我会回到这里，
and so this is the kind of layout of the steps I took.
这就是我采取的步骤的布局。
Are there any questions on that particular solution before I move on?
在我继续之前，对这个解决方案，有什么问题吗？
Can you please elaborate a little more on the conditional variable?
你能更详细地说明一下条件变量吗？
Sure, so, what exactly, I guess like a conditional variable is,
当然，所以，我想条件变量是，
very useful,
非常有用，
for when you want to wait for a particular predicate or particular condition to become true,
当你想要等待特定断言或特定条件变为真时，
so in this case, condition variable is a natural,
所以在这种情况下，条件变量是自然的，
let me just go to where I use,
让我到我用到的地方，
is a natural way to implement waiting for there to be a task available,
是实现等待可用任务的自然方式，
because you know it's a particular condition,
因为这是一种特殊的条件，
and it occurs asynchronously,
而且它是异步发生的，
so for example a task is available,
例如，有一项任务可用时，
when a worker has finished a task,
当 worker 完成一项任务时，
or task might be available when the, when a failure occurs,
或任务可能可用，在发生故障时，
and we need to reissue the task,
我们需要重新发布这项任务，
so you can think of,
所以你可以想到，
any case in which, you need to wait for a particular condition,
在任何情况下，你需要等待特定的条件，
that's where condition variables become very helpful.
这就是条件变量非常有用的地方。
Does that help a little bit?
这会有一点帮助吗？
Yeah, thank you.
是的，谢谢。
You can also,
你也可以，
like all of these higher level,
比如所有这些更高级的，
like channels, condition variables,
比如通道、条件变量，
all these higher level synchronization primitives actually,
所有这些更高级的同步原语，
they're built on top of locks,
它们都是构建在锁上的，
so they're all implemented using locks,
所以它们都是使用锁实现的，
is just there,
是一种，
kind of a higher level way of thinking about synchronization,
一种更高层次的思考同步的方式，
that allows you to [reason] for example about conditions.
这让你可以推断条件。
Would that have the same effect,
这会有同样的效果吗，
as for example sleeping in that loop,
比如在那个循环里，
that you have in the GetTask function
你在 GetTask 函数中，
instead of like having a condition variable,
不是使用条件变量，
that makes the loop run every second,
它使循环每秒运行一次，
I guess.
我想。
Yeah, so, it it is, like it's essentially the same as sleeping,
是的，所以，它本质上和睡眠一样，
the, so the loop here, the timeout loop here,
这里的超时循环，
the difference is that,
不同的是，
for example, the condition variable,
例如，条件变量，
or you could be woken up by a task that has completed,
你可能被一项已经完成的任务唤醒，
where in a loop, in which you sleep for example a second every single loop,
在循环中，例如睡眠每秒循环一次，
you have to wait a second,
你必须等待一秒，
whereas with a condition variable,
而对于条件变量，
you could be woken up after you know like ten milliseconds,
你可会在大约 10 毫秒后被唤醒，
because the worker has completed a task,
因为 worker 已经完成了一项任务，
so it potentially has better liveness properties.
所以，它可能具有更好的灵活性。
By this case, we do like say,
在这种情况下，我们使用，
if every task always takes over like five seconds or something,
如果每项任务总是占用 5 秒左右的时间，
then yes, this is essentially very similar to sleeping for one second every loop.
那么，是的，这本质上非常类似于每个循环睡眠一秒。
I have a question,
我有个问题，
I think I missed the part where you run,
我想我错过了你运行的部分，
how you handle, when a request comes for a task,
当任务请求到来时，你如何处理，
but you're like there's no tasks to give out currently,
但你目前没有任务要分配，
like you, how do you tell the worker to like sort of either come back
你怎么告诉 worker 要么回来
or do you keep them waiting
还是让它们等待，
and sort of [tangentially] to that,
一带而过地，
I'm curious why you chose this like sleep way of doing it,
我很好奇，你为什么选择这种睡眠的方式，
instead of just like checking the time when you get request for tasks,
而不是收到任务请求时查看时间，
and seeing, like when you get a request,
比如当你收到请求时，
what has timed out and reissuing it,
已经超时，并重新发布它，
then instead of like constanly checking.
而不是不间断的检查。
Yeah, okay, so,
是的，好的，所以，
yeah, so I'll just your first question first,
是的，所以我先问你的第一个问题，
so basically how I handle the completed the task,
所以我是如何处理已经完成的任务的，
is once all Map tasks have finished,
是一旦所有的 Map 任务完成，
once all Reduce tasks have finished,
一旦所有 Reduce 任务都已完成，
then the task that we return to the worker,
然后我们返回给 worker 的任务，
because the worker has called us task for task
因为 worker 调用的任务，
is this extra task type, that I called Done,
是这个额外的我称为 Done 的任务类型，
and then I also set that the coordinator isDone to true,
然后我设置 coordinator 的 isDone 为 true ，
and so in the workers,
所以在 worker 中，
I'll go to the worker,
我现在去 worker 中，
and the worker we have this loop,
worker 中我们有这个循环，
that basically as the worker is asking for tasks,
当 worker 要求任务时，
if it that returned tasks is a Done task, then it exits.
如果返回的任务是 Done 任务，它就退出。
So that's how I handle conveying to the worker,
所以这就是我向 worker 传达信息的方式，
that it should exit.
它应该退出。
I guess I was asking like,
我想我是在问，
sorry, if you know let's say you're still finishing up on your Map tasks,
抱歉，比如你还在完成 Map 任务，
and you get requests for a task,
你收到任务的请求，
and you still can't give out your Reduce tasks,
你仍然不能给出你的 Reduce 任务，
how do you tell the worker?
你怎么告诉 worker 呢？
Oh, so, a lot of you are,
哦，所以，你们中的很多人都是，
an alternative design is to,
另一种设计是，
basically if the worker, if there's no task to give the worker,
如果没有任务给 worker ，
then the coordinator returns a reply to the worker immediately,
然后 coordinator 立即向 worker 返回回复，
and the worker sleeps in its loop,
而 worker 在它的循环中睡眠，
but you can see here, right,
但你可以在这里看到，
the worker loop, there is no sleep,
worker 循环，没有睡眠，
and the reason for this is,
其中的原因是，
because this call will block until the coordinator replies,
因为这个调用会阻塞直到 coordinator 回复，
and in my solution,
在我的解决方案中，
going back to the coordinator,
回到 coordinator ，
for example like if you look at mapDone,
例如，如果你查看 mapDone ，
in this solution, the coordinator handler will not return that reply to that call,
在这个解决方案中， coordinator 处理程序不会向那个调用返回回复，
unless it has a task to return,
除非它有任务要返回，
so it's, we're waiting in the coordinator rather than in the worker.
所以，我们是在 coordinator 那里等待，而不是在 worker 那里。
So the coordinator is the one,
所以 coordinator 就是那个，
that is constantly checking to see whether there's a task and sleeping,
不断地检查是否有任务和睡眠，
whereas the worker just simply blocks on this call,
而 worker 只是简单地阻塞在这个调用上，
until the coordinator returns to it.
直到 coordinator 返回给它。
Is there any advantage to doing it in the coordinator?
在 coordinator 中这样做，有什么好处吗？
So I think one advantage is that,
所以我认为一个优势是，
all the workers aren't constantly sending RPCs,
并不是所有的 worker 都不断地发送 RPC ，
you send an RPC,
你发送一个 RPC ，
it's one RPC per task, right,
这是每个任务一个 RPC ，
whereas if the worker is constantly looping and sleeping and constantly reply,
而如果 worker 不断地循环和睡眠，并且不断地回答，
you have a lot more network traffic.
你会有更多的网络流量。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah, I think that's, but definitely both solutions are feasible,
是的，我认为这是，但这两种解决方案都是可行的，
and they both work.
它们都是可工作的。
Great.
太棒了。
I had one other question,
我还有一个问题，
which is I I I see you use a defer for the locking quite a bit,
我看到你经常对锁使用 defer ，
while I was doing my implementation,
当我在做我的实现时，
I I realized,
我意识到，
I mean in a straightforward function,
我的意思是，在一个简单的函数中，
it, it's clear,
它很明显，
when it gives up control of the lock,
什么时候放弃对锁的控制，
but for example if you, like have a goroutine created from within the function,
但是如果你有一个从函数内部创建的 goroutine ，
it's not very clear, when it gives up control.
就不是很清楚，何时放弃控制。
So, a goroutine runs on a separate thread,
所以，一个 goroutine 在单独的线程上运行，
so the goroutine never starts with the lock acquired,
goroutine 永远不会从获取的锁开始，
even if you spin off the goroutine, while you hold the lock.
即使当你持有锁时，开始那个 goroutine 。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
嗯。
If we, if we issue like a Go, if we create a goroutine,
如果我们创建一个 goroutine ，
it'll just spin up a thread,
它只会在一个线程中旋转，
and from the beginning, it won't have a lock, right?
而且从一开始，它就不会有锁，对吗？
Yeah, it's actually just like,
是的，实际上就像，
you know you think about another thread
你认为另一个线程
just starting to run that Go, like Go func, that function.
开始运行 Go 函数。
Yeah.
嗯。
Yeah, go ahead.
好的，继续。
And then defer unlocks at any return, like any return statement there?
然后 defer 在任何 return 语句解锁？
Yep, yeah, it's pushed onto a,
是的，它推到一个，
like basically like the functions to run when the,
比如函数运行，
there's a stack of functions,
有一个函数的堆栈，
that the returning from like HandleGetTask will run,
比如 HandleGetTask 运行返回，
so, I also have this in the slides,
所以，我在幻灯片中也有这个，
so you'll be able to refer to this later,
所以你稍后可以看的这个，
but defer just ensures that when this function exits,
但 defer 只是确保当这个函数退出时，
you over you around unlock,
你使用解锁，
and then I could also do something, like unlocking,
我还可以做一些事情，比如 unlocking ，
and like I could just do something, like before the last printf or println,
我也可以做一些事情，比如 before the last println ，
so these are all pushed onto a stack,
所以这些都被压到一个堆栈上，
and then they're popped off in FIFO order, no, LIFO order.
然后它们按先进先出的顺序弹出，不，是后进先出的顺序。
What FIFO?
什么 FIFO ？
First in first out, no they're run in last in first out, yeah,
先入先出，不，它们是后进先出，是的，
so it's a stack right,
所以这是一个堆栈，
so this will run before unlocking,
所以这将在解锁之前运行，
which will actually run before the lock,
在锁之前运行，
so if you're ready to use multiple defers,
如果你准备使用多个 defer ，
be careful in the order, then use them,
注意顺序，然后使用它们，
but defer the unlock at least is a very useful strategy,
但 defer unlock 是一个非常有用的策略，
that will come in handy.
这会派上用场的。
Okay, so the last thing is,
好的，那么最后一件事是，
if we call a function within within our our function,
如果我们在函数内调用函数，
where we acquire the lock,
在那里我们获得了锁，
it doesn't return the lock, right,
它不会返回锁，对吧，
when it goes to the other function,
当它转到另一个函数时，
the other function returns to this function,
另一函数返回到这个函数，
and then until we, like the thread keeps a lock, like through like jumping around.
然后，比如线程保持者锁，通过跳来跳去。
Yeah, so like a function,
是的，一个函数，
that's just like a normal function call within one thread,
就像一个线程中的普通函数调用，
will be called with the lock out, yes.
将在锁的情况下被调用，是的。
Cool, thanks.
好的，谢谢。
Yep.
好的。
Alright, so you guys have already kind of discussed
好的，你们已经讨论了
some of the alternate synchronization designs,
一些备用的同步设计，
like waiting in the worker rather than the coordinator,
比如在 worker 而不是在 coordinator 等待，
and we've talked about some of the pros and cons of that,
我们讨论了这样做的一些利弊，
using time,
使用 time ，
actually I think already covered all of these except for channels maybe,
事实上，我认为已经涵盖了所有这些，可能除了通道，
so there's one thing I wanted to know,
所以有一件事我想知道，
because there are a couple questions about this,
因为对此有几个问题，
so waiting for map has to be done
所以等待 map 完成，
or like any synchronization that we've shown
或者我们展示的任何同步
is on a single server,
都在一台服务器上，
so cross-server communication between the worker and the coordinator,
所以 worker 和 coordinator 之间的跨服务器通信，
they're only, it's only done ever by RPCs,
它们只是通过 RPC ，
so for example like locking in the coordinator
例如，在 coordinator 的锁，
has nothing to do with locking on the worker,
与 worker 的锁无关，
or on interactive implementation locking on different servers,
或者在不同服务器上的交互实现锁上，
like don't interfere with each other,
不会互相干扰，
I just want to be clear about that.
我只想澄清这一点。
So one thing I thought would be interesting is,
所以我觉得有一件事会很有趣的是，
for you to see a kind of an example using channels,
为了让你看到一种使用通道的例子，
because there are also some questions using channels, about using channels.
因为这里也有一些问题关于使用通道。
So this is kind of,
所以这是一种，
is a not complete implementation of using channels,
不是一种完全使用通道的实现，
but it's a potential way to,
但这是一种潜在的方式，
but you could think about having used channels in MapReduce.
你可以考虑在 MapReduce 中使用通道。
And so in this example,
所以在这个例子中，
the input to the coordinator actually includes a channel,
到 coordinator 的输入包含一个通道，
in which the coordinator is told of what workers exist,
其中 coordinator 被告知哪些 worker 存在，
and this is to handle the possibility that workers are failing,
这是为了应对 worker 失败的可能性，
and then some client is telling the coordinator,
然后某个客户端告诉 coordinator ，
hey, this other worker joined our cluster,
嘿，另一个 worker 加入了我们的集群，
here's a new worker, that you can give tasks to,
这是一个新 worker ，你可以给它分配任务，
so it's slightly different than what we had in the lab.
所以，这与我们在实验中的略有不同。
So the coordinator has two channels,
所以 coordinator 有两个通道，
one in which it will send tasks to workers
其中一个，它会发送任务给 worker ，
or it won't send tasks to workers,
或者它不向 worker 发送任务，
will send tasks to a thread, that will issue tasks to workers,
将任务发送到线程，线程将向 worker 发送任务，
and then it has a done channel.
然后它有一个 done 通道。
So again, just like,
所以再一次，
I I know I said something a little strange,
我知道我说了一些奇怪的话，
which I was like you can send tasks to workers over the channel,
你可以通过通道向 worker 发送任务，
but you actually can't,
但实际上不能，
the channel is only on the coordinator on your server,
通道只在你的服务器上的 coordinator ，
and we'll see how that works in a second.
稍后我们再来看它是如何工作的。
So the first thread of the coordinator that we create is a goroutine,
所以，我们创建的 coordinator 的第一个线程是 goroutine ，
that basically will for every worker, start the issueWorkerTaskThread.
对于每一个 worker ，开始 issueWorkerTaskThread 。
So, what this does is,
所以，这样做的目的是，
as workers are you know coming and going,
作为 worker 来来去去，
because they're failing and then restarting,
因为它们失败了，然后又重启，
this channel basically says,
这个通道表示，
okay, we want to, for any of these workers,
好的，我们想要，对于任何一个 worker ，
start a thread that will issue this worker tasks.
启动一个将会发布这个 worker 任务的线程。
So this is one goroutine here,
所以这里一个 goroutine ，
then the coordinator what it does is it,
然后 coordinator 所做的是，
for all the tasks that were giving,
对于所有给出的任务，
it just push those tasks onto this tasks channel,
它只是将这些任务推到这个 tasks 通道，
and this tasks channel,
而这个 tasks 通道，
we actually made it a buffer channel,
我们让它是一个缓冲通道，
so that we know it will hold exactly numTask tasks,
这样我们知道它能准确地容纳 numTask 个任务，
which are the that's the limit of the number of tasks,
这就是任务数量，
that will exist on the system,
将存在于系统中的，
so what this also means is that,
所以这也意味着，
we can push the numTask tasks onto this channel without blocking,
我们可以在不阻塞的情况下将 numTask 个任务推到通道，
so the coordinator will not block on pushing task to the tasks channel.
所以， coordinator 不会阻塞将任务推送到 tasks 通道。
And then the coordinator will read from this done channel
然后 coordinator 将从这个 done 通道读取，
until it has done so numTask times,
直到它完成 numTask 次，
in which case, it knows it's done,
在这种情况下，它知道它已经完成了，
in this case, where I'm not separating map or reduce tasks,
在这个例子中，我没有区分 map 或 reduce 任务，
let's just imagine that there are,
想象一下它们在那里，
some number of tasks that the coordinator needs to run.
coordinator 的一些任务需要运行。
And once it knows that tasks, all the tasks have finished,
一旦它知道所有的任务都完成了，
it closes the tasks channel, and then basically will exit.
它关闭 tasks 通道，然后将退出。
And so the, where some of the interesting part comes in is,
所以，其中一些有趣的部分是，
these worker task threads,
这些 worker 任务线程，
which I've separated out and just function here.
我把它们拿出来，放在这里。
So, these all run on sub goroutines,
所以，这些都是在子 goroutine 上运行，
and what it does is for,
它所做的是为了，
as long as there are tasks in the task queue,
只要 task 队列中有任务，
it will pull a task out,
它将拉出一项任务，
and then oops, I didn't mean to that,
然后，哦，我不是故意的，
and then call basically an RPC,
然后调用一个 RPC ，
that will send the task to the worker,
它会将任务发送给 worker ，
so note that,
所以注意到，
this channel actually is talking to another thread of the coordinator,
这个通道正在与 coordinator 的另一个线程交互，
and that thread is actually the one that's in charge of calling the worker,
而那个线程是负责调用 worker 的那个线程，
and then once it's done with the task, it says it's done,
然后一旦它完成了任务，它就会说已经完成了，
if it's not able to, if the call fails,
如果它不能，如果调用失败，
for some reason, for example it times out,
因为某些原因，比如它超时了，
then, what this loop does is,
然后，这个循环所做的是，
it'll push that task back onto the tasks channel,
它会将该任务推回到 tasks 频道，
so another worker or potentially this thread again could pick up that task.
所以，另一个 worker 或这个线程可能会再次执行这个任务。
So just to clarify how the channel communication works,
因此，为了说明通道通信是如何工作的，
so the worker sends tasks on the tasks channel,
所以 worker 发送任务到 tasks 通道，
which is read through these loops,
通过这些循环读取，
and this loop will exit when the coordinator closes the channel,
这个循环将在 coordinator 关闭信道时退出，
done, it's sent on these worker, issue worker threads,
done ，它被发送到这些发送的 worker 线程，
and it's read by the coordinator, the original coordinator thread
它被原始的 coordinator 线程读取，
and this exit equals true,
这个 exit 等于 true ，
will basically tell the coordinator,
将会告诉 coordinator ，
like, oh, I don't need to listen for any more workers coming or workers starting up,
哦，我不需要听更多的 worker 到来或 worker 开始，
so it will cause this other goroutine to exit.
所以它会导致另一个 goroutine 退出。
So I know that this is a pretty complex example,
我知道这是一个相当复杂的例子，
it's also not quite what we specified in the lab,
这也完全不是我们在实验里指定的，
but as an example of how channels can be used,
但是作为如何使用通道的一个例子，
to implement something like MapReduce or something similar to MapReduce.
来实现 MapReduce 或类似 MapReduce 的东西。
There is a question in the chat,
聊天中有一个问题，
about where's exit define in this code?
关于 exit 在代码中的哪里定义？
That is a good question,
这是个好问题，
it's not,
它没有，
so it'll, it'll be exactly the same thing is done,
它会跟 done 一样，
it will just be another channel that's a boolean, yeah,
它将是另一个布尔值的通道，是的，
that's a good, a good catch.
这是一个很好的发现。
Oh, can I?
哦，我可以？
I've seen.
我看到。
How do you add things to the workers channel,
如何将东西添加到 workers 通道，
or when you add things to the workers channel,
或者当你向 workers 通道添加东西时，
like how do you handle them in this case?
在这种情况下，你是怎么处理它们的？
Yeah, so in this case,
是的，所以在这种情况下，
worker, the workers channel is provided to the coordinator,
workers 通道提供给 coordinator ，
so imagine that, for example,
想象一下，举个例子，
and you know how your Coordinator
你的 Coordinator
was actually called or created by the MR coordinator in main,
是被 main 中的 MR coordinator 调用或创建的，
in the that [],
在那个[]中，
so we would imagine that in MR coordinator,
所以，我们可以想象，在 MR coordinator 中，
we would create a workers channel,
我们会创建一个 workers 通道，
and MR coordinator would basically be in charged of tracking,
MR coordinator 将负责跟踪，
when workers crash and when workers join,
什么时候 workers 崩溃，什么时候 workers 加入，
so this is for example in a case,
所以这是一个例子，
where you know maybe new servers are added to our cluster at some later point
可能稍后会有新服务器添加到我们的集群中，
or some worker crashed and then came back,
或者某个 worker 崩溃，然后又回来了，
and MR coordinator would be constantly sending,
而 MR coordinator 会不断地发送，
like these worker ids to our Coordinator,
这些 worker id 给我们的 Coordinator ，
in order to tell it, hey, like there's new worker,
为了告诉它，嘿，这里有一个新的 worker ，
you should start issuing it tasks,
你应该给它发布任务，
so that part is not shown.
这部分没有显示出来。
Got it, yeah, I just I just wondering like,
明白了，是的，我只是在想，
so that's really cool,
所以这真的很酷，
I was just wondering inside the lab 1,
我只是想在实验 1 中，
like how I think it's like call worker and you've sends RPC to the worker,
我想调用 worker ，你发送 RPC 给 worker ，
if if that's something we could have done in lab 1?
我们在实验 1 中可以这么做吗？
It's possible it,
这是可能的，
but it definitely was not what we pushed you toward,
但这绝对不是我们让你们去做的，
because you would basically,
因为需要，
instead of setting up the coordinator as being RPC server,
不是将 coordinator 设置为 RPC 服务器，
you would have to set up like RPC servers on the workers,
你必须在 worker 是设置 RPC 服务器，
you can also think of,
你可以认为，
in this implementation, call_worker could have handlers actually for each worker,
在这个实现中， call_worker 可以为每个 worker 设置处理程序，
and each worker could be sending the coordinator like that task RPCs,
每个 worker 可以发送 task RPC 给 coordinator ，
but a little, that's a little [],
但这有点[]，
so in this example is actually more natural to imagine,
所以在这个例子中，可以更自然的想象，
that call_worker, the coordinator is a client,
那个 call_worker ， coordinator 是一个客户端，
and the workers are the ones that are handling that RPCs.
而 worker 就是处理那个 RPC 的人。
Yeah, okay, thanks, very cool.
好的，谢谢，很酷。
I have two questions,
我有两个问题，
first is just a generally Go question,
首先，这只是一个一般性的 Go 问题，
so in that second for loop on the left, at the bottom,
所以，在左侧底部第二个 for 循环中，
if you don't use i, will Go complain for, in a for loop?
如果你不使用 i ， Go 会在 for 循环中抱怨吗？
So I run like all the Go linter and all that stuff
所以我运行了所有的 Go linter 以及类似的东西，
and it's fine, I think,
我觉得这是可以的，
like, in this case, you do you need to have i,
在这种情况下，你需要 i ，
because you're incremented and keeping the state of i around through the.
因为你是递增的，在整个过程中保持 i 的状态。
Can you do the same thing,
你能做同样的事情，
with like a like a while loop,
比如一个 while 循环，
like just for empty for loop with a select,
比如空的 for 循环加上一个 select ，
where it's like popping off of done.
在那里弹出 done 。
So, you can't actually,
所以，你不能，
well, you still need to keep track of how many times you've read from done, right,
好的，你还是需要记录一下你读了多少次 done ，
because you can't just read once,
因为你不能只读一次，
you have to read numTask times.
你必须读取 numTask 次。
I see, okay.
我明白了，好的。
Yeah, yeah, so you do need some type of state that will track that.
是的，所以你需要某种类型的状态来追踪这个。
And then for for the one on the right,
然后对于右边的那个，
like where you're reading from tasks and re-populating it,
你从 tasks 中读取并重新添加它，
is there like any downside to that,
这有什么不好的地方吗，
if you're like just constantly reading and adding back and forth to the same channel?
如果你不断地读取和添加到同一个通道？
I don't, I can't think of that the top my head,
我想不出来，
so in this case, at least you won't block,
所以在这种情况下，至少你不会阻塞，
because every time you read it,
因为每次你读到它，
you're popping something off the channel,
你会在通道上弹出一些东西，
every time you add it, you're pushing something,
每次你添加它，你推送一些东西，
so because we have that the tasks is a buffer channel,
因为我们有 tasks 是一个缓冲通道，
but you'll never block on that.
但你永远不会阻塞这个。
So, in terms of like performance,
所以，对于性能方面，
I think, I mean channels are built using locks,
我的意思是，通道是用锁建造的，
so locks are usually more lightweight,
所以锁通常更轻，
but I don't think, I don't think, you'll see a huge performance in fact,
但我不认为，你会看到一个大的性能，
doing something like this.
做这样的事。
Okay, I guess, I've like a,
好的，我想，比如，
sorry, just like a general question of like,
抱歉，比如一个一般的问题，
what's your like calculus for choosing
你是如何计算并选择，
between Mutex and channels or like a hybrid,
在 Mutex 和通道或混合之间，
at the very beginning.
在最开始的时候。
Yeah, so Mutex are very natural for just protecting a piece of state,
是的，所以 Mutex 对于保护一个状态来说是非常自然的，
so like your Coordinator or like your Raft servers have a log,
比如你的 Coordinator 或你的 Raft 服务器有日志，
I want to protect everytime I append the log,
我想在每次添加日志时保护，
that seems very difficult or it seems very unnatural
这看起来很难或很不自然，
to try and do using channels,
在这里尝试使用通道，
because essentially, you'd be using the channels lock,
因为从本质上讲，你使用通道锁，
you'd want to ensure that no one else is modifying the state,
你想要确保没有其他人在修改状态，
while you're modifying it,
当你修改它的时候，
and then you would have to essentially before you modify it,
然后在你修改它之前，
try to read on the channel to ensure that no one else,
试着从通道读取，确认也没有人，
alright, like someone would have to send something on the channel,
好的，比如某些人必须发送东西给通道，
just show that they've done,
只是表示它们已经完成，
they've been finished modifying so and so forth.
它们已经完成了这样或那样的修改。
So, in that case, it's actually very hard to imagine how you do channel,
所以，在这种情况下，很难想象你如何使用通道，
where Mutex would make that completely straightforward,
Mutex 会让这个变得非常简单，
where channels come in very handy is,
通道非常方便的地方是，
like I think our implementation already has this apply channel,
我认为我们的实现已经有了 apply 通道，
is where you have to wait for,
是你必须等待的地方，
in some ways, it's almost like a specific instance of a condition variable,
在某些方面，它就像条件变量的特定实例，
in which you want to wait for something to be ready,
在这种情况下，你想要等待什么东西准备好，
or a, like a very specific type of command to be finished,
或者像是一种要完成的非常具体的命令，
so for something like issuing tasks is actually not a bad example
所以，对于像发布任务这样的事情来说，是一个不错的例子，
or something like blocking until you have something on a queue,
或者诸如阻塞在一个队列上，
like is you can almost think of it as like a queuing system,
你可以把它想象成一个队列系统，
or at least that's how I like to think about it,
或者至少我是这么想的，
but, for almost all modifications to shared state,
但是，对于共享状态的几乎所有修改，
like the race conditions [], encounter locks are much simpler
比如竞争条件，遇到锁要简单得多，
and in some ways, a lot easier to reason about,
在某些方面，推理要容易得多，
but, yeah.
但是，是的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Sorry, I have a follow up question to this slide,
抱歉，我有一个关于这张幻灯片的后续问题，
what happens if the,
如果，会发生什么，
so you call the Go issueWorkerTaskThread,
所以，你调用 Go issueWorkerTaskThread ，
which spins up another goroutine,
它会启动另一个 goroutine ，
I mean, it goes through all the tasks in the channel,
我的意思是，它遍历通道中的所有任务，
what if it fails,
如果它失败了，
when it's what if the goroutine fails,
如果 goroutine 失败了，
when it's sitting on the if call_worker.
当它位于 if call_worker 时。
So, if it fails,
所以，如果它失败了，
then I guess you've taken a task out and not put back,
那么我想你拿出了一个任务，没有把它放回去，
I'm actually not sure, that seems like,
其实我也不确定，这看起来像是，
like you're not,
比如你不是，
you're saying like the entire thread crashes, rather than as call_worker,
你说的是整个线程崩溃，而不是 call_worker ，
not like returning fails or something.
不是返回失败或什么东西。
Yeah, like the goroutine crashes,
是的，比如 goroutine 崩溃，
or is that possible for a single goroutine to fail
或者单个 goroutine 可能失败吗，
or would like the entire thing just blow up?
或者整个事情都没了？
Hey, Frans, you know?
嘿， Frans ，你知道吗？
I think the model you should have is that,
我认为你应该拥有的模型是，
if a goroutine crashes, the process crashes.
如果 goroutine 崩溃，那么进程也会崩溃。
Yeah, that would solve it.
是的，这样就能解决了。
Sorry, so if just the worker crashes,
抱歉，如果只有 worker 崩溃了，
then you pick a different task,
然后你选择一个不同的任务，
but, should you,
但是，如果你，
I guess you would still have the same worker,
我想你仍然会有相同的 worker ，
like worker number,
比如 worker 编号，
so you still connect to the same worker, even though they have failed.
所以，你仍然连接相同的 worker ，即使它们崩溃了。
Yeah, so in this case,
是的，所以在这种情况下，
basically call_worker would just continue returning false,
call_worker 只会继续返回 false ，
and you know this goroutine that's specific for this worker,
这个 worker 专门的 goroutine ，
we just continue to loop,
我们只是继续循环，
and eventually when the map,
最终，当 map ，
when the coordinator has determined that all the tasks have finished,
当 coordinator 确定所有任务都已完成时，
it'll close the channel and then this goroutine will exit.
它将关闭通道，然后这个 goroutine 将退出。
So there could potentially like,
所以有这种可能性，
if all your workers continue crashing,
如果你所有的 worker 持续崩溃，
you have like hundreds of new workers joining,
你有数以百计的 worker 加入，
like you could potentially have a lot of goroutines just there,
你可以会在这里有很多 goroutine ，
just like I can't contact my worker,
我不能联系我的 worker ，
but once the task is finished,
但是一旦任务完成，
this all of them will exit properly.
这一切都将正常退出。
Cool, alright,
酷，好的，
so that's an example with channels,
这是一个通道的例子，
and now let's move on to some of the
现在让我们转到一些
more like your questions and bugs and things like that.
你们的问题和错误之类的事情上。
So some common but passing design mistakes that we saw
所以，我们看到的一些常见但通过的设计错误
was pushing too much work to the coordinator,
是把太多的工作交给了 coordinator ，
so essentially making the coordinator bottleneck,
这会使 coordinator 成为瓶颈，
and this included both the coordinator [],
这包括 coordinator [] ，
sorting the results or the coordinator reading file contents,
对结果排序或 coordinator 读取文件内容，
whereas a lot of the kind of beauty of MapReduce is that,
然而， MapReduce 的许多优点在于，
all the state, all the computation happens on the workers.
所有的状态，所有的计算都发生在 worker 上。
And another con, it's not really a mistake,
还有另一个缺点，这并不是一个真正的错误，
but potentially something to think about is,
但潜在的需要考虑的是，
how many RPCs are you sending,
你要发送多少 RPC ，
and like, do you really need to send that many RPCs.
你是否真的需要发送那么多 RPC 。
So for example sending an RPC to check whether there's a Map task available,
例如，发送 RPC 检查是否有可用的 Map 任务，
and then sending another RPC to ask like give me a task,
然后发送另一个 RPC 要求给我一个任务，
is a little redundant
是有点多余的
and you want to try and reduce the number and types of,
你想试着减少，
like reduce the API between the master, the coordinator and the worker,
减少 coordinator 和 worker 之间的 API ，
but these were, like they were passed the test,
但这些，它们通过了测试，
and it's just things we wanted to point out.
这只是我们想指出的一些事情。
So now, okay cool, what about like how I do lecture.
所以，现在，好的，酷，我接下来的课程。
So, for the next, say like 5 6 minutes,
所以，接下来，比如 5 6 分钟，
what we're going to do breakout rooms,
我们要做的是分组会议室，
let let me stop sharing actually,
让我来停止分享，
alright, so do breakout rooms,
好的，开始分组会议室，
and oh shoot, let's see,
哦，糟糕，让我看看，
I think Zoom just crashed on me.
我想我的 Zoom 刚刚崩溃了。
We could still hear and see you.
我们仍然可以听到和看到你。
Alright, I'm back,
好了，我回来了，
yeah, I upgraded Zoom before this lecture,
是的，我在这节课之前升级了 Zoom ，
that was a bad idea,
这不是个好主意，
but, alright, for the next 5 or 6 minutes,
但是，好的，在接下来的五六分钟里，
you should talk about just like
你应该讨论，
you know any interesting bugs or observations, you had about lab,
你在实验中任何有趣的 bug 或观察，
or you could you know complain about how long it took you to find a certain bug
或者你可以抱怨你花了太长时间才找到某个漏洞，
or ask questions to each other,
或者互相提问，
and then we'll come back and go over some of your questions.
然后我们会回来，讨论你们的一些问题。
Alright.
好的。
Alright, see you in a bit.
好的，待会见。
Oh, so with Frans,
哦， [] 和 Frans 一起，
do you want me to [] somewhere else?
你想让我重新分到别的组吗？
Probably best, but let me see if I can do it myself.
也许是最好的，但让我看看我自己能不能做到。
Okay, I'm going to be right back.
好的，我马上回来。
Alright, are we mostly back, I think.
好的，我想我们差不多都回来了。
Alright cool.
好的，酷。
Okay, so I hope that was pretty fun
好的，我希望这很有趣，
or at least you got to talk about some of your frustrations during the lab.
或者至少你可以谈谈你在实验中的一些挫败感。
Yeah, so for the rest of the lecture,
是的，对于剩下的课程，
we're going to go to,
我们要去，
first, before questions,
首先，在提问之前，
take some general tips,
给出一些一般的提示，
that you'll want to look out for for future labs.
你要在未来的实验中注意。
So first of all,
所以，首先，
the one thing you'll find very handy for debugging is just
你会发现调试非常方便的一件事是，
you know classic printfs
经典的 printf ，
and so you can have conditional printfs,
你可以使用有条件的 printf ，
which only print when you want to debug,
只有当你想 debug 时打印，
so for example you don't have to go through your code
所以，你不必遍历代码，
and comment them all out,
把它们都注释掉，
before you submit or something like that,
在你提交或做类似的东西之前，
and so in the Raft lab,
所以在 Raft 实验里，
we provide this DPrintf in the util.go file,
我们提供了 DPrintf 在 util.go 文件中，
and you can modify that to for example also print out like the server ID,
你可以对其修改，打印出比如 server ID ，
every single time you call DPrintf or something like that,
每次你调用 DPrintf 或类似的地方，
so, yeah, I customize it
所以，是的，我定制了它
to you know print out different colors for different RPCs,
用不同的颜色来打印不同 RPC ，
like that,
就像这样，
and also like redirecting your output files,
还可以重定向你的输出文件，
just so you can like search the files will come in handly.
如果你需要搜索就会很方便。
Another trick that you probably want to keep in mind is,
另一个你可能要记住的技巧是，
you can look at all the goroutines
你可以查看所有 goroutine ，
to see where and their execution, they're running,
看看它们在哪里运行，
and so just type Ctrl-\ in order to do that.
只需要输入 Ctrl-\ 来做到这个。
And the final thing which already sort of talked about are these defers,
最后一个是我们已经谈到过的 defer ，
and these slides will be uploaded also,
这些幻灯片也将被上传，
so you can refer back to them,
所以你可以回来参考它们，
but actually you can push multiple functions
但是你可以推入多个函数，
to run right before the function returns
在函数返回之前运行，
and they just be careful of the ordering.
只是要注意它们的顺序。
Alright, so now let's get to some of your questions,
好的，现在来回答你们的一些问题，
a lot of you submitted also questions about Raft,
你们中的许多人也提交了关于 Raft 的问题，
so those will get to for the Raft Q&A
这些会放到 Raft 的问答，
or maybe office hours
或者办公时间
or you can put that on Piazza.
或者你可以把它放在 Piazza 上。
I'm going to focus mostly on the ones from MapReduce
我将主要集中在 MapReduce 中的那些，
or maybe have time, then we can also get Raft questions.
或者，也许有时间，我们也可以看一些 Raft 问题。
Alright, so the first category of questions
好的，第一类问题，
kind of falls under questions specifically about MapReduce,
是专门关于 MapReduce 的问题，
so some more complex tasks that you might want to use MapReduce for,
所以，你可能需要使用 MapReduce 来执行一些更复杂的任务，
it's actually used a lot in ML, or like data mining, statistical applications,
它在机器学习、数据挖掘、统计应用中被大量使用，
I linked here to Hadoop,
我在这里链接到 Hadoop ，
which is implements MapReduce,
它实现了 MapReduce ，
a lot of people use it to run these types of tasks.
很多人使用它来运行这些类型的任务。
And for example, here's a simple,
例如，这是一个简单的，
or maybe not so simple,
也可能不是那么简单的，
but basically matrix multiplication example,
但是矩阵乘法的例子，
of how you would [] that using MapReduce.
你如何使用 MapReduce 来[]它。
Second, like you for fault tolerance of the coordinator,
第二，对于 coordinator 的容错，
the paper proposes a very simple checkpointing mechanism,
论文提出了一种非常简单的检查点机制，
in which you'll just start up a new coordinator,
你只需要启动一个新的 coordinator ，
using the last checkpoint state,
使用最新的检查点状态，
and in some ways, this is a very natural design for MapReduce,
在某些方面，这是 MapReduce 非常自然的设计，
because everything is deterministic,
因为一切都是确定性的，
there's no,
这里没有，
the coordinator really doesn't have that much state to hold,
coordinator 没有那么多的状态要保持，
all I need to know is
我所需要知道的是
which have finished and which has happened.
哪些已经结束，哪些已经发生。
So you could use Raft of course to enable fault tolerance,
当然，你可以使用 Raft 来实现容错，
and have a set of coordinators,
并拥有一组 coordinator ，
that all agree on the commands issued so far and the current state,
这些 coordinator 都同意之前的命令和当前状态，
but in some ways, it seems a little overkill for the coordinator,
但在某些方面，这对 coordinator 来说有点过了，
for something that's more stateful,
对于更有状态的东西，
it's like a key value store or something,
比如键值存储或其他什么东西，
it's much more natural to use a Raft.
使用 Raft 要自然得多。
So some other questions about MapReduce,
所以关于 MapReduce 的其他一些问题，
the shuffle or combiner step,
shuffle 或组合器步骤，
when does it happen and what does it do,
它在什么时候发生，它是做什么的，
so combining occurs like right after the Map functions applied,
组合就发生在 Map 函数应用之后，
for example, in combining the word counts of a particular word,
例如，组合特定单词的单词计数，
because having a lot of entries,
因为有很多条目，
that you know like the one you could you know combine them,
你可以把它们组合在一起，
and then write only that to the mediate file, intermediate file,
然后将其写入中间文件，
sorting occurs at the reduce,
排序在 reduce 时进行，
after all the outputs of the map are read by the reducer.
在 reducer 读取了 map 的所有输出之后。
Let's see,
让我们看看,
is successor to MapReduce,
是否有 MapReduce 的后继者，
yeah, so actually, I'm not super familiar with it,
是的，我不是很熟悉，
but you can look at stuff like Google Cloud Dataflow,
但你可以看看比如 Google Cloud Dataflow ，
and other sort of directed graph computations,
以及其他的有向图计算，
where inputs flow into a node,
在输入流入节点的情况下，
so you can think of as graph,
所以你可以把它想象成一张图，
and then they might flow out to other nodes,
然后它们可能会流向其他节点，
and that node in the middle [] performs for example map computation,
中间的节点执行 map 计算，
and produces intermediate data,
并产生中间数据，
is then sent to other like reducer that in the graph,
然后发送到其他图中的 reducer ，
so it's a interesting way,
所以这是一种有趣的方式，
it's like a data dataflow way to think about MapReduce.
是一种数据流的方式来思考 MapReduce 。
And I'm sure that there's others that,
我相信还会有其他的，
I'm not [] like that where.
我不知道在哪里。
I did, one, maybe one of them Spark,
我知道，可能其中一个是 Spark ，
which we'll read later about.
我们将在后面读到。
Yeah, so, but I I like the graph way of thinking about MapReduce,
是的，但是我喜欢用图的方式来思考 MapReduce ，
because right now we're only really thinking about a two-step operation,
因为现在我们考虑的只是两步操作，
where it could actually be like you know many many steps.
在那里，它可能是很多很多步。
Oh, yeah, then how input partitioned in practice,
哦，是的，那么在实践中输入是如何划分的，
so, usually, because the input space is very application specific,
通常情况下，因为输入空间是特定于应用程序的，
and output space is also application specific,
并且输出空间也是特定于应用的，
it's really up to the programmer to specify,
这是要由程序员来指定，
there's sometimes a natural division,
有时会有自然划分，
for example make a local matrix computation,
比如做一个本地的矩阵计算，
then you want to combine them or so on so forth,
然后你想把它们组合起来，等等，
or you could if it's just like an enormous document or like enormous text text files,
或者，如果它只是一个巨大的文档或巨大的文本文件，
you can just split it up into a reasonable size of work,
你可以把它分成合理大小的工作，
so you know like applying the map function is going to take []
所以应用 map 函数会[]，
and also depends on the size of your cluster,
还取决于你的集群的大小，
so how many workers you have.
你有多少 worker 。
So some further MapReduce questions,
还有一些关于 MapReduce 的问题，
why do mapper store files locally,
为什么 mapper 在本地保存文件，
so in the paper,
所以在这篇论文中，
this is because at that time, the network bandwidth was their bottleneck,
这是因为在当时，网络带宽是他们的瓶颈，
that's why they don't use GFS,
这就是为什么他们不使用 GFS ，
they only use GFS to write the,
他们只使用 GFS 写入，
yeah, to write the output files.
是的，写入输出文件。
Are leaders necessary for distributed systems,
领导者是分布式系统所必需的吗，
not necessarily,
不一定，
there, like, think of Bitcoin, like other decentralized systems,
考虑比特币，其他去中心化系统，
in which all the nodes sort of perform competition,
其中所有节点都进行了竞争，
and some random node or like some node in the network
网络中的某个随机节点或某个节点，
is responsible for committing that,
负责提交它们，
so there are definitely more like egalitarian designs.
所以肯定有更平等主义的设计。
Oh, yeah, our challenge was
哦，是的，我们的挑战是
actually to run MapReduce on like actual different servers
在不同的服务器上运行 MapReduce ，
rather than what we kind of had you do in the lab,
而不是我们让你在实验里所做的，
and so in order to do this,
所以，为了做到这一点，
like you just,
你需要，
instead of using sockets to communicate over for like RPCs,
不是使用 sockets 来为 RPC 通信，
you would use like TCP/IP,
你应该使用 TCP/IP ，
basically like normal, like over the network communication,
正常地通过网络进行通信，
and you would use a shared file system like GFS,
你可以使用像 GFS 这样的共享文件系统，
so the [] I think all of you have access to Athena,
我认为你们所有人都可以访问 Athena ，
if at least at MIT,
至少在麻省理工学院，
and you know ssh to multiple Athena machines,
ssh 到多台 Athena 机器，
and use AFS which is the file, shared file system,
并使用 AFS 文件共享系统，
I think Athena uses too,
我想 Athena 也用了，
basically, you can access your files on Athena from any machine,
基本上，你可以从任何机器访问你在 Athena 上的文件，
similarly you could do the same thing by rent AWS instances and using S3,
同样，你也可以通过租用 AWS 实例并使用 S3 来做同样的事情。
but we didn't expect you to spend any money to run our lab.
但我们没想到你会花钱来运行我们的实验。
Right, so some questions that came about, just like general code design,
好的，有一些问题，比如通用代码设计，
so we've some of these we've discussed as well,
所以我们也讨论了其中的一些，
so lab 1 was pretty small,
所以实验 1 很小，
lab 2 is going to be much larger,
实验 2 将变得更大，
especially as you get to the later stages,
尤其是当你进入后期阶段时，
and as lab 3 and lab 4 come along as well.
实验 3 和实验 4 也是一样。
And one thing that I personally find very handy is,
我个人觉得很方便的一件事是，
just separate different chunks of code by their purpose,
按其用途分隔不同的代码块，
so, and also in how I implement each step of my code,
在我如何实现代码的每一步时，
so separating them out by,
所以把它们分开，
for example RPCs and the senders and handlers,
比如 RPC ，以及发送者和操作者，
and feel free to actually separate these out physically in different files,
可以自由地将它们物理地分开放在不同的文件中，
that won't,
那不会，
like that's fine for a test,
这对测试来说也是可以的，
and it will probably help you,
它可能会对你有所帮助，
like not have thousands of lines of code in one gigantic file.
不会在一个巨大的文件中有数千行代码。
I I personally like to put all definitions of state together,
我个人喜欢把所有状态的定义放在一起，
and then functions are like sort of separate,
然后，函数是分开的，
but that's my personal preference,
但这是我的个人喜好，
factoring out common pieces of code into functions will also be very helpful,
将常见的代码片段分解为函数也将非常有用，
for example every single RPC, you will get in Raft,
例如你在 Raft 中的每个单独的 RPC ，
you need to check for stale term,
你需要检查过期的 term ，
so putting all that logic,
所以将所有的逻辑，
so that resets all the state properly and everything
把重置所有状态和所有东西
into one function, that you just call,
放到你要调用的一个函数中，
will help,
将会有所帮助，
because you know you don't want to accidentally forget to
因为你不想不小心忘记
reset your election timer or like reset votedFor or something,
重置选举定时器或重置 votedFor 或某些东西，
although you shouldn't reset the election timer,
虽然你不应该重置选举定时器，
so don't do that,
所以不要那么做，
that was an example I pulled off the top of my head.
这只是我脑海中浮现的一个例子。
And also finally have a good environment
最后有一个好的环境，
with like autocomplete or like being able to search for certain keywords in your code,
比如 autocomplete 或者能够在代码中搜索某些关键字，
and so forth can help a lot.
这样的事情会有很大帮助。
So if you need any help setting this,
所以如果你需要任何帮助来设置这个，
like come to office hours
可以在工作时间来，
or there's tons of tutorials online,
或者网上有大量的教程，
you can look up a good editor,
你可以找一个好的编辑器，
but it's not necessary, it's definitely not necessary,
但这不是必要的，绝对不是必要的，
but it could it does help.
但这可能会有所帮助。
And then, oh yeah, so has using Go decrease the amount of time students spend debugging,
然后，是的，使用 Go 减少了学生花在调试上的时间，
so I've never actually implemented the labs in C++,
所以我从来没有用 C++ 实现过这些实验，
but according to Frans, like,
但根据 Frans 的说法，
well, the one huge advantage of Go is its memory management,
Go 的一个巨大优势是它的内存管理，
so uses garbage collection,
使用垃圾收集，
and don't have to deal with,
你不需要处理，
like you know there are pointers,
这里有指针，
but you don't have to deal with them in the same way you would see your C++,
但你不必像 C++ 那样处理它们，
so like, I don't know how many of you run into segfaults so far,
我不知道你们中有多少人遇到了分段错误，
but I'm guessing very few of you
但我猜你们中很少人，
or they were very easy to fix,
或者它们很容易修复，
and this definitely makes it easier to debug,
这无疑使调试变得更容易，
or they're just certain types of bugs that you don't need to worry about.
或者它们是你不需要担心的特定类型的 bug 。
Sorry, I have a question.
抱歉，我有个问题。
Yeah.
好的。
This is like a more Go specific question,
这是一个 Go 的问题，
but when you have a function that can take in,
但当你有一个可以接受的函数时，
let's say you have like a, you have a appendEntries arg,
假设你有一个 appendEntries 参数，
and you also have like a requestVote arg,
而且你也有一个 requestVote 参数，
both of them have a term variable inside,
它们里面都有一个 term 变量，
but when you pass it to a function,
但当你将其传递给函数时，
how do you tell the function,
你怎么告诉这个函数，
that's like, hey I expect a struct, that has a term field,
比如，我想要一个结构，它有一个 term 字段，
is that possible?
这有可能吗？
So you define the types right,
所以，你定义了类型，
so it's like any other type,
它就像任何其他类型，
when you pass into the function,
当你传递到函数中时，
the function expects an argument of a particular type,
函数需要特定类型的参数，
and that's type.
这是类型。
Yeah.
嗯。
Yeah, let's say I want to share one function across both types.
是的，假设我想在这两种类型之间共享一个函数。
I believe you can use an interface,
我相信你可以使用 interface ，
but I'm not sure.
但我不确定。
So I tried to, but when I do .term,
所以我试过了，但当我做 .term 时，
it says I don't know this field
它说我不知道这个字段，
or like it doesn't exists.
或者它不存在。
I think you need to convert it
我想你需要转换它，
or you need to just give a casting,
或者你需要转换，
I can't remember,
我想不起来了，
but there's a way to coerce.
但有一种方法可以强制。
You have to type cast it back,
你必须对它进行类型转换，
you know to whatever struct you want access.
到你想要访问的 struct 。
Like you basically need to talk Go,
比如你需要高数 Go ，
that by the time, I actually use this variable,
这个时间，我使用这个变量，
it is of a particular type.
它是一种特定的类型。
Got it, thank you.
知道了，谢谢。
So one thing if you want to reuse the function for multiple different types,
所以，如果你想对多个不同类型重复使用该函数，
you can pass in an interface,
你可以传入一个接口，
but you might also need to pass in,
但你可能还需要传递，
for example, like you know more [] something that tells it,
例如，比如某些东西来告诉它，
like, hey this is going to be this type,
嘿，这将是这种类型的，
and then you need to cast that interface into the right type, before you use it.
在使用它之前，需要将该接口转换为正确的类型。
Okay.
好的。
I think the way people usually handle this is,
我认为人们通常处理这件事的方式是，
by putting setters and getters in the interface,
通过在接口中放置 setter 和 getter ，
you don't actually know which type it is in actuality,
你不知道它是哪种类型的，
you just access the variable using interface.
你只需使用接口访问变量。
Yeah.
嗯。
Yeah, I don't think it,
是的，我不这么认为，
you shouldn't need to use interfaces that much in Raft,
你不应该在 Raft 中使用很多 interface ，
I don't think I used it all,
我不认为我使用了它，
other than the command which is provided.
除了已经提供的命令。
Yeah, like, I guess factoring out common pieces of code is good,
是的，我想分解出常见的代码片段是很好的，
unless it adds additional complexity,
除非它增加了额外的复杂性，
like I wouldn't try and force your types,
我不会试着强迫你的类型，
to all be able to run on the same function,
为了所有都能够在相同的函数上运行，
like it might just be similar type,
它可能是相似的类型，
two slightly different functions.
两个略有不同的函数。
Or, if the only like shared piece you're using is the term,
或者，如果你使用的唯一分享是 term ，
you can have the same function taken just the term,
你可以有相同的函数只接受 term ，
and in both cases, pass in the .term of the struct using.
在这两种情况下，都传入 struct 的 .term 。
Alright, some other code design questions?
好的，还有其他代码设计问题吗？
Once when separating the code into multiple files,
当将代码分成多个文件时，
is there naming conventional like required,
有没有按要求命名的惯例，
because when we make the lab,
因为当我们做实验的时候，
it seems like it's copying the source file,
它是复制源文件，
so is there any naming convention?
那么有没有什么命名约定呢？
I mean, I would put them in raft, the raft folder,
我的意思是，我会把它们放在 raft 文件夹中，
but there's no naming convention,
但没有命名约定，
like you can name your files whatever you want.
你可以随意地命名你的文件。
Okay, our grading scripts will replace anything,
好的，我们的评分脚本将替换任何东西，
that's necessary for or anything that belongs to the testing framework,
属于测试框架的任何东西，
so the config file or like the test file,
所以，配置文件或测试文件，
anything that you change in there will be wiped out.
你在里面修改的任何东西都会被抹去。
Yeah.
嗯。
Like also be slightly careful about using external dependencies,
在使用外部依赖时也要稍加小心，
I ran into a couple issues with grading some scripts,
一些评分脚本，我遇到一些问题，
I had external dependencies,
我有外部依赖时，
like using some github package, Go package,
比如使用一些 gitHub Go 包，
but those were I was able to fix it,
但这些都是我能修好的，
just be a little careful, if you do that.
如果你这么做了，要小心一点。
But, yeah, create as many .go files in raft as you want.
但是，是的，创建你所需要的 .go 文件。
Yeah, so pointer versus a value, while passing by reference can be cheaper,
是的，所以指针和值比较，传递引用会更便宜，
because Go won't just copy the struct,
因为 Go 不会复制那个 struct ，
this was, this question was asked
这个问题被问到，
in particular for why call takes the arguments
特别是为什么调用使用参数，
and the reply as pointers,
而回复使用指针，
and so yeah those could be potentially extremely large,
是的，这些可能是非常大的，
and so Go doesn't have to copy them, when you call the function,
所以 Go 不需要复制它们，当你调用函数时，
that's the main reason.
这是主要原因。
Using both locks and channels are possible?
可以同时使用锁和通道吗？
Yes, you'll give them both in Raft,
是的，你可以在 Raft 中同时是因为它们，
so you will definitely see how it's possible.
所以你肯定会看到这是如何可能的。
Oh yeah, and then we're getting a lot of questions about timeouts,
哦，是的，然后我们收到了很多关于超时的问题，
so in map, in the MapReduce lab,
所以在 MapReduce 实验里，
the timeout was sort of,
超时时间是，
well, we gave you a 10 seconds for the worker tasks when they [],
我们给 worker 任务 10 秒钟时间，
but in terms of how long do you sleep,
但对于睡眠时间来说，
and that were pretty much able to choose anything other that.
可以选择其他的任何时间。
For Raft, you have to choose timeout a little more carefully,
对于 Raft ，你必须更仔细地选择超时，
and our tests are like kind of sensitive, but not super sensitive,
我们的测试有点敏感，但不是非常敏感，
like you'll be [] for example,
例如，你可能[]，
probably be within a range of one to 100, to 200 milliseconds,
可能在 100 到 200 毫秒的范围内，
and be fine.
都是可以的。
Yeah, in terms of choosing them,
是的，对选择它们来说，
probably helps to first think about why you're waiting at all,
可能会有帮助，先想想你为什么需要等待，
and for example in the, for Raft,
例如，对于 Raft ，
your leader is sending heartbeat,
你的领导者发送心跳，
and your timeout is to detect when the leader is dead,
你的超时用来检测领导者停机，
so, you kind of want to give the leader a couple chances
所以，你想给领导者几次机会
to tell you that it's alive,
告诉你它还活着，
otherwise you know you'll just continuously think it's dead,
否则你会一直认为它已经死了，
so depending on what you set your heartbeat timeout to be
所以，根据你设置的心跳超时，
or your heartbeat interval to be,
或者你的心跳间隔，
which I think will give you some guidelines of,
我认为这会给你一些指导，
it can't be ten more than ten times per second or something like that,
它每秒不可能超过十次，或者类似的东西，
depending on what you set your heartbeat,
取决于你设定的心跳，
you'll want your timeout to be something, like pretty reasonable,
你会希望你的超时时间是合理的，
like maybe allow for the chance to get two to three heartbeats,
也许可以有机会得到两到三次心跳，
and then you'll have to randomize some like range,
然后你必须随机化一些范围，
because you don't want all your servers start elections at the same time,
因为你不想让你所有的服务器同时开始选举，
and to do that, you can you know like a range of,
要做到这一点，你可以有一个范围，
maybe like two to five heartbeats,
可能有两到五次心跳，
some timeout between there is reasonable,
在这两者之间的某个超时时间是合理的，
but in terms of the test,
但是对于测试，
you'll see whether you're sending too many RPCs
你将看到是否发送了太多的 RPC ，
or too many bits are going over the network
或者网络上传输的比特太多，
as the test go in later labs,
随着测试在后面的实验中，
and you can tweak your timeout very easily,
你可以很容易地调整你的超时时间，
it's slightly implementation dependent,
它稍微依赖于实现，
so, I can't tell you like what's the perfect number for you,
所以，我不能告诉你最适合你的数字是多少，
but thinking of it, in terms of why am I timing out in the first place,
但考虑，为什么我要超时，
and how many RPCs do I want to get from like other servers before timeout,
在超时之前，我希望其他服务器获得多少 RPC ，
is a good metric to keep in mind,
是一个值得牢记的好的指标，
hopefully, that helps a lot of timeouts.
希望这对超时有很大帮助。
Okay, yeah, so some implementation questions,
好的，是的，所以一些实现的问题，
that came up about the MapReduce lab,
关于 MapReduce 实验，
and also the labs in general.
还有一般的实验。
So, some people actually did implement backup tasks,
所以，有些人实现了备份任务，
which is pretty cool,
这是相当酷的，
and we definitely did not require that for this lab,
我们在这个实验中绝对不需要这样做，
and I think something that was important to keep in mind is that,
我认为需要记住的重要一点是，
the paper has makes a distinction between starting, restarting a task,
论文对开始任务和重启任务做了区分，
because a worker has failed,
因为一个 worker 失败了，
and issuing the task again,
并再次发布任务，
to speed up a lagging task,
加快滞后任务的速度，
that the worker hasn't failed,
worker 并没有失败，
but you want the task to complete faster,
但是你希望更快地完成任务，
and so backup tasks are used for the lagger,
所以，备份任务用于落后者，
when tasks are haven't failed yet,
当任务还没有失败时，
but there's there just slow and timeout,
但是速度很慢并超时，
we start task,
我们开始任务，
when workers are actually detect to fail.
当 worker 检测到失败时。
So when the paper,
所以，在论文中，
the coordinator actually gets heartbeats from the workers,
coordinator 从 worker 那里得到心跳，
whereas in the design that we propose for your lab,
而在我们为你的实验提出的设计中，
we use timeouts both to detect that worker has probably failed
我们使用超时来检测 worker 可能出现失败，
and also to detect slow tasks,
同时还检测缓慢的任务，
so in some ways, we make that we don't have that distinction,
所以，在某些方面，我们没有这种区别，
we just assume that,
我们只是假设，
if this task hasn't been completed in this set of time,
如果在这段时间内没有完成这项任务，
that you know like probably the worker has failed
可能是 worker 失败了，
or maybe it's just insanely slow,
或许它只是慢得让人抓狂，
and let's reissue it,
让我们重新发布它，
so that's why our labs don't really mention backup tasks.
这就是为什么我们的实验没有提到备份任务。
So, and then, yeah so there, this is again going back to the confusion,
所以，然后，是的，所以，这又回到了困惑，
the next question, about like synchronization,
下一个问题，关于同步，
if the servers are on different machines,
如果服务器位于不同的机器上，
so the servers are on different machines,
所以，服务器位于不同的计算机上，
and they only communicate using RPCs,
而且它们只使用 RPC 进行通信，
all synchronization is just protecting or synchronizing the threads on one server,
所有同步只是同步一台服务器上的线程，
I just want to emphasize that one more time.
我只想再强调一次。
Common source of race conditions, just you know logging,
通常的代码竞态条件，比如日志，
I, in some ways I think,
在某些方面我认为，
someone's talking about,
有人在说，
like you know how do you know when to lock,
什么时候使用锁，
and how do you know when to use synchronization,
以及什么时候使用同步，
so anytime you're modifying the state of the file,
所以，每当你修改文件的状态时，
like your Raft server or the coordinator,
比如 Raft 服务器或 coordinator ，
anytime you modify the state,
任何时候你修改状态时，
you want to lock,
你需要加锁，
and what you'll notice is that,
你会注意到，
for almost every function in your Raft implementation, for example,
例如，对于你的 Raft 实现中的几乎每个函数，
you will have a lock
你会有一个锁，
and then a defer unlock, like right after that.
然后在那之后，一个 defer unlock 。
The only time you need to make sure that you're not lock is,
你唯一需要确保你没有被锁的时候是，
when you make a call on might block,
当你在可能阻塞的地方调用时，
so sending an RPC,
所以，发送 RPC ，
you know sending something over channel,
通过通道发送一些东西，
those type of operations, you shouldn't lock around,
那些类型的操作，你不应该锁在那里，
because then you're, you're that thread will just be blocked on that,
因为然后那个线程会被阻塞，
and hold the lock and stop the server,
然后持有锁并停止服务器，
any thread on the server from making progress.
服务器上的任何线程都不会取得进展。
Yeah, and then there are some questions about like,
是的，然后有一些问题，
there are some data races they're benign,
有些数据竞争是良性的，
like for example you could set isDone to be true,
例如，你可以设置 isDone 为 true ，
and you know like you don't really need to lock around that,
你并不需要把对它加锁，
but the race detector is complaining,
但是竞争检测器会抱怨，
you could use an atomic []
你可以使用原子[]，
which has the same behavior, like locking before unlocking after,
它具有相同的行为，先锁定后解锁，
but even though you might think this data race is benign,
但是，即使你认为这个数据竞争是良性的，
it's undefined behavior,
这是一种未定义的行为，
so it just so happens, that you know eventually the next read,
所以碰巧的是，最终下一次读取，
like your read might miss the fact, that isDone,
你的读取会忽略 isDone 的事实，
but the next time you call isDone, it will say true,
但下次你调用 isDone 时，它会说是 true ，
and then you're fine,
然后你就好了，
but undefined behavior could technically be implemented as anything,
但从技术上讲，未定义的行为可以实现为任何东西，
like it just so happens that your compiler
比如碰巧你的编译器，
and your processor does something reasonable,
你的处理器会做一些合理的事情，
when there's a data race,
当出现数据竞争时，
so you should handle them especially when they're simple,
所以你应该处理它们，特别是当它们很简单的时候，
and they don't really affect performance that much.
而且它们对性能的影响并不是很大。
Another thing is,
另一件事是，
well, in in theory, you could have this like is [] data race,
嗯，在理论上，这种[]数据竞争，
could potentially mean that your process would never exit,
可能意味着你的进程永远不会退出，
because you know the write to isDone, setting it to true,
因为写入到 isDone ，将它设置为 true ，
might ever actually propagate to the thread that's reading,
可能会传播到正在读取的线程，
what whether it's true or not,
无论它是否为 true ，
because it could be stored in some like buffer and never flushed,
因为它可以存储在某种缓冲区中，并且永远不会被刷新，
what locks ensure is that,
锁确保的是，
your write the next thread that reads is done,
你的写入，下一个读取的 isDone ，
will see the last write isDone,
将看到最新的写入 isDone ，
and actually flush it,
并且刷新它，
from for example a potential buffer that the write could be stored.
从写入可以保存的可能的缓存区中。
So, yeah, that's just emphasizing,
所以，是的，这只是强调，
like you don't want data races,
你不想要数据竞争，
even if you think that they're really friendly.
即使你认为它们很友好。
Clean way to exit?
干净的退出方法？
So sending an exit RPC from coordinator to worker, workers,
所以，发送一个 exit RPC 从 coordinator 到 worker ，
also like the quote unquote like messy Exit,
也像引号中的 Exit ，
where the worker tries to send RPCs,
worker 尝试发送 RPC ，
the socket is closed,
socket 已经关闭，
like those are also fine,
这也是可以的，
like most solutions are equally acceptable.
大多数解决方案也是可以接受的。
And then unexpected EOF errors,
然后是意外的 EOF 错误，
so, you can look I have a link here,
所以，你可以看到，我在这里有一个链接，
that it shows when it's invoked the client,
当它被客户端调用时它会显示，
but it's a little confusing as to when that actually happens,
但这让人有点困惑，在什么时候发生，
so I would not worry about it too much,
所以我不会太担心，
if any one has insights into,
如果有人能观察到，
if they got this error at a very strange moment,
如果他们在一个非常奇怪的时刻得到这个错误，
then we could look into it,
然后我们可以调查一下，
but I think it's very specific on your implementation,
但我认为这对你的实现是非常具体的，
so I would have to look at that, in particular,
所以我必须专门看一下，
but we got a bunch of questions about that.
我们有一堆问题是关于它的。
Yeah, I think so that's basically most of the questions that came up,
是的，我想这就是出现的大多数问题，
and I think now if you have any questions about you know Go, MapReduce
我想现在如果你有任何关于 Go MapReduce 的问题，
or if you want to ask staff about the labs.
或者如果你想向工作人员询问实验的情况。
I had a question about the clean way to exit.
我有一个关于干净退出方式的问题。
So you're saying like something Exit RPC,
所以你说 Exit RPC ，
I was just wondering if there were like,
我只是想知道有没有，
if there was like a case,
是否有这种情况，
where a worker for some reason just takes a very long time to reach the server, right,
worker 出于某种原因需要很长时间才能到达服务器，
like how like how does the server know,
服务器如何知道，
like when to like shutdown,
比如什么时候关闭，
because, because because the coordinator shutdown at some point, correct,
因为 coordinator 在某个时候关闭，
when, when, when it says like done, when done returns true,
当它说 done ， done 返回 true 时，
it shutdown and so it stops replying to the workers,
它关闭，停止回复 worker ，
how does it decide when to do that,
它如何决定什么时候这样做，
if it's waiting for, for workers to shutdown themselves.
如果它在等待 worker 自己关闭。
Oh, so in this case, the coordinator isn't,
哦，所以在这种情况下， coordinator 不会，
oh I guess,
哦，我想，
so send is probably the wrong word,
所以发送可能是个错误的词，
the coordinator isn't waiting for the workers to respond,
coordinator 不是在等待 worker 回复，
the coordinator is not sending it's replying to the request from workers,
coordinator 没有回复 worker 的请求，
with a, like the task is done, please exit,
比如任务已经完成，请退出，
the worker isn't,
worker 不是，
the coordinator isn't actually waiting for the workers at all,
coordinator 根本不是在等待 worker ，
and so in this case,
所以，在这种情况下，
the coordinator could actually still exit before the workers,
coordinator 仍然可以在 worker 之前退出，
and cause the workers to like,
并让 worker ，
you know have a disconnected socket error and exit.
出现套接字断开错误并退出。
Yeah, I I guess, that was my question really,
是的，我想我的问题是，
like like if if it I could though,
如果我可以的话，
coordinator replying to workers, right,
coordinator 回复 worker ，
that are like potentially like asking for get task,
可能在请求任务，
but what happens if the worker shutdown,
但如果 worker 关机会发生什么，
or sorry the coordinator shutdown,
或者抱歉， coordinator 关闭，
before it gets, get get task RPC from the worker.
在它从 worker 获得 RPC 之前。
Oh, then the next time the worker tries to contact the coordinator,
哦，那么下一次 worker 试图联系 coordinator 时，
the worker will see that the connection is closed and then exit.
worker 将看到连接已关闭，然后退出。
Yeah.
嗯。
That's as clean shutdown as we'll get.
这是我们能得到的最干净的关闭了。
Essentially, I mean you could imagine that,
基本上，我的意思是你可以想象，
you know you could set up the workers to be RPC servers,
您可以将 worker 设置为 RPC 服务器，
then you would actually have the coordinator be sending these, like please exit,
然后 coordinator 会发送这些，比如请退出，
the coordinator will have to wait for the workers to exit,
coordinator 必须等待 worker 退出，
but it's not,
但它不是，
or it doesn't seem like you won't get any utility out that.
看起来你不会从中得到任何效用。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Yeah.
嗯。
Kat, I see you have your hands.
Kat ，我看到你举手了。
Yeah, something that I was wondering about is,
是的，我想知道的是，
for the future labs, are we allowed to have more files,
对于未来的实验室，我们允许有更多的文件，
I think explicitly in the MapReduce lab,
我认为在 MapReduce 实验中，
we were only supposed to have three,
我们只有三个，
and it didn't read something where it was like,
它并没有读到像这样的东西，
hey, you should have all of your stuff contained in one.
嘿，你应该把你所有的东西都放在一个里面。
Oh, yeah, so you can definitely add more files,
哦，是的，你肯定可以添加更多的文件，
that's like I would almost encourage that,
我会鼓励你那样做，
I, did we say that about MapReduce,
我们有没有说过这个，关于 MapReduce ，
I I don't, I can't remember whether.
我不记得有没有。
What you saying, you couldn't edit any of the other main files,
你说你不能编辑其他任何主文件，
it like.
它就像是。
Yeah, you couldn't edit the [], yeah.
是的，你不能编辑[]，是的。
Okay, I misread that, thanks,
好的，我理解错了，谢谢，
this makes me feel a lot better.
这让我感觉好多了。
Yeah, yeah, but definitely like bring your code will be useful.
是的，但是带上你的代码肯定是有用的。
I have a question about the benign data races,
我有一个关于良性数据竞争的问题，
I guess like,
我想是这样的，
because sometimes there's for example raft,
因为有时候比如 Raft ，
you just want to read the current state of the of the Raft server,
你只需要读取 Raft 服务器的当前状态，
why would multiple write, multiple threads writing to it and one reading,
为什么多个线程写入和一个读取，
so why would a read and write to the same variable,
那么为什么对同一变量的读取和写入，
end up cause undefined behavior,
最终导致未定义的行为，
because it read comes before or after the write.
因为它在写入之前或之后读取。
So, one thing that can happen,
所以，有一件事可能会发生，
and most processors don't do this,
大多数处理器不会这样做，
but, every time you have a,
但是，每次你有一个，
like so these any thread can run on a separate core,
比如，任何线程都可以在单独的核心上运行，
and every core has a buffer,
每个核心都有一个缓冲区，
for the data that it's reading or writing,
对于它读取或写入的数据，
or writing, I guess like a store buffer,
或者写入，我想是一个存储缓冲区，
so for example thread 1 could write one value to the state,
所以，例如线程 1 可以向状态写入一个值，
and thread 2 could try to read it,
线程 2 可以尝试读取它，
or like multiple threads can be writing,
或者多个线程可以写入，
and thread 1 without a lock,
线程 1 没有使用锁，
so locks essentially flush the buffer,
锁会刷新缓冲区，
without that lock,
而没有锁，
this write might just like stay in thread 1's, like store for forever,
这个写入会永远停留在线程 1 的存储，
and the read will never return the updated value,
而读取将永远不会返回更新值，
so this behavior doesn't quite happen in practice,
这种行为在实践中并不经常发生，
but it's an allowable behavior,
但这是一种允许的行为，
because you do not have a lot.
因为你拥有的并不多。
Sorry, so what happens if the write has a lock,
抱歉，如果写操作有锁会发生什么，
but the read doesn't,
但是读取没有，
like does the read always need a lock?
比如，读取总是需要锁吗？
Yes, because, I think of it.
是的，因为，我想是的。
I I googled a little bit,
我用谷歌搜索了一下，
and people are like, yeah, don't, don't even try lock-less share data,
人们会想，是的，不要尝试无锁共享数据，
but I don't really understand why that would be a problem.
但我真的不明白为什么这会是个问题。
So it's.
所以，它是。
You could like.
你可能会。
Go ahead.
继续。
You could like be doing something that assumes the thing was true,
你可能做一些假设事情是 true 的事情，
and then like when you read,
然后当你读取时，
it's not actually true yet,
它还不是 true ，
like there might be multiple things, right,
这里可能有多个事情，
that's why you don't want to lock this read.
这就是你为什么不对读取加锁。
So the only time you might be able to even get away with this is,
所以你能避免这个的机会是，
if you only read a single word,
如果你只读取一个字，
and that's all the thread does,
这就是线程所做的一切，
and it never does multiple reads,
它不进行多次读取，
but I think you still have some issues with.
但我认为你还是有一些问题。
One of the other things is,
另一件事是，
if you're reading more than one piece of data,
如果你读取多个数据，
like if on one thread, you take lock, assign a assign b,
比如在一个线程上，你获取锁，分配 a ，分配 b ，
another thread, it doesn't take a lock,
另一个线程，它没有获取锁，
might see b, the new value of b,
可能会看到 b 的新值，
before it sees the new value of a,
在它看到 a 的新值之前，
the ordering that you messed up,
你弄乱了顺序，
and so if you read like a term from one that, from one variable
所以，如果你从一个变量中读取 term ，
and like whether not the leader from another variable,
而领导者从另一个变量中读取，
you might read a pair of values that never actually existed,
你可能会读到一对根本不存在的值，
because there aren't the guarantees,
因为没有保证，
like when you're [] to concrete systems,
当你[]具体的系统时，
you need to build everything based off what the guarantees are the platform provides you,
你需要基于平台提供的保证来构建所有内容，
and if you don't,
如果你不这么做，
there's all kinds of weird edge cases that can throw you off,
有各种各样奇怪的边缘情况会让你不知所措，
and yeah.
而且，是的。
Yes, so I think the only case in which you can even,
是的，所以我认为唯一能让你，
like try to reason about this,
比如对此进行推理，
is this, is this there's only ever one like you know word in the system,
就是系统中只有一个字，
that you're ever trying to read and write to,
你试图读写的，
as soon as you try to write or read multiple pieces of data,
只要你尝试写入或读取多个数据片段，
then it's like you won't be able to reason about anything without locks.
如果没有锁，你就不能对任何事情进行推理。
Basically, if you want to play games with this,
基本上，如果你想玩这个游戏，
you have to really understand the compiler,
你必须真正理解编译器，
the whole [] language and memory model,
整个[]语言和内存模型，
the processor you're using
你正在使用的处理器，
and it's like memory consistency system,
比如内存一致性系统，
it gets complicated, incredibly [].
它变得极其复杂。
Yeah, it's also like, I mean this is all undefined behavior,
是的，这也是，我是说，这都是不确定的行为，
so even if it works now,
所以即使它现在起作用了，
like you know I could, someone could write a new compiler,
比如，我可以，有人可以编写一个新的编译器，
and then you're, like that's where the whole thing about,
然后整件事，
like demons can fly out of your nose,
就像恶魔可以从你的鼻子飞出（http://catb.org/jargon/html/N/nasal-demons.html），
like it can literally do anything, if you have a data,
比如它可以做任何事情，如果你有数据的话，
it's because like other programs like, doesn't have any semantic,
因为其他程序没有任何语义，
so we can like go crazy,
所以我们可能导致疯狂，
so I would I would not risk it.
所以我不会冒险。
Okay, it makes sense, thank you.
好的，理解了，谢谢。
So, so even when we're accessing like anything,
所以，即使当我们读取任何东西时，
just reading, let's say Raft server state,
比如只是读取 Raft 服务器的状态，
we should still wrap it in a lock.
我们还是应该对它加锁。
Yeah.
是的。
It just gets annoying sometimes,
有时候会很烦人，
because you have to like,
因为你必须，
wrap the single read in a lock and unlock,
把单个读取放在 lock 和 unlock 之间，
but I'm not sure like knows [].
但我不确定[]。
That shouldn't happen super often,
这种情况不应该经常发生，
like I mean, maybe if you want to for example check you're still a leader,
我的意思是，也许如果你想确认你仍然是领导者，
if you're not exit or something like that,
如果你不退出或诸如此类的，
but, yeah, I don't, like, I forget,
但是，是的，我不是，
do you use like atomic bools for like killed state for example,
你是不是用原子布尔型表示杀死状态，
that like you could use a [],
你可以使用[]，
which essentially is like locking and unlocking right before accessing it and right after,
在访问它之前和之后，加锁和解锁，
but, yeah,
但是，是的，
I think you'll like having in some ways very coarse-grain locks,
我想在某些方面有非常粗粒度的锁，
and knowing that you're the only one touching a piece of state,
知道你是唯一访问状态的那个，
will become very handy as you reason about your implementations.
将在你对实现进行推理时变得非常方便。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I have a question about the channels,
我有一个关于通道的问题，
so when you make a channel,
所以当你制作一个通道时，
it's only between two threads, right,
它只是在两个线程之间，
or it can be between multiple threads,
或者它可以在多个线程之间，
but like if you not, if you don't have buffered,
但是如果你没有缓冲，
it can potentially just lock and block forever, right,
它可能会永远阻塞，
so, for example, if you want to do something in Raft,
所以，比如，如果你想在 Raft 中做一件事，
and then you have an election,
然后你有一个选举，
you have a channel that like,
你有一个通道，
does something about election timeouts,
做一些关于选举超时的事情，
you will need a buffer channel,
你需要一个缓冲通道，
that's like the size of the amount of servers, correct,
就是服务器数量的大小，
because you could like send something and then like it blocks,
因为你可以发送一些东西，然后它会阻塞，
because, you can be,
因为，你可以，
you can have multiple like election things,
你可以有多个像选举这样的东西，
election messages sent between the channels, correct,
在通道之间发送的选举信息，
so if you want a unbuffered channel,
所以如果你想要一个没有缓冲的通道，
it should only be between, it should only be between two threads only, correct?
它应该只在两个线程之间，是吗？
I mean not necessarily,
我的意思是不需要，
like if two threads are consumers,
例如，如果两个线程是消费者，
and one thread is producer,
一个线程是生产者，
that the.
那是。
Okay, but multiple producers, I guess you would need that, correct?
好的，但是多个生产者，我想你需要，是吗？
Well, not necessarily,
嗯，不需要，
I mean, if the consumer is,
我的意思是，如果消费者只是，
you know just doing a loop and constantly reading,
在做一个循环，并不断读取，
then all the producers would just,
然后所有的生产者都会，
like, I guess it depends on how they schedule,
我想这取决于它们是怎么调度的，
by if,
如果，
you're like you would eventually have someone reading from the channel,
最终会有人从通道上读出，
so you can have multiple producers and one consumer.
所以你可以有多个生产者和一个消费者。
Actually, does anyone know about the, like Frans,
有没有人知道，比如 Frans ，
do you know about the ordering guarantees of channels,
你知道通道的顺序保证吗，
like is their [] guarantee on you,
是否有[]保证给你，
I feel like there is an [] guarantee,
我觉得有一个[]保证，
so I guess if you have,
所以我想如果你有，
it's kind of like lock, right,
有点像锁，
like if you're always trying to acquire the lock,
比如，你总是试图获取锁，
another thread is also spinning and trying to acquire the lock,
另一个线程也试图获取锁，
there's no guarantee that you will ever require it,
不能保证你会获取它，
which is why like randomization might be necessary in that case,
这就是为什么在这种情况下随机化可能是必要的，
also I realized I think this lecture is technically over,
我意识到，我认为这节课从技术上讲已经结束了，
I am holding the office hours right now,
我现在继续在办公时间，
so if you have questions along to
所以如果你有问题要问，
or want to continue asking questions,
或者想继续提问，
I'll be there
我会在那里，
and I think maybe Frans,
我想也许 Frans ，
if you want to stick around or other, others.
如果你想留下来或其他人。
But I will move to the office hours, now,
但我现在要去办公时间了，
so, thank you all so much for coming.
所以，非常感谢你们的到来。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Oh, can I just ask a quick question?
哦，我能问个简单的问题吗？
Yeah, alright, Frans, you're the host now,
是的，好的， Frans ，你现在是主持人了，
so I'm going to just hop off to my office hour.
我要去我的办公时间了。
And what is the theme of the your Vim?
你的 Vim 的主题是什么？
Oh, what's the scheme, like my color scheme.
哦，方案是什么，我的配色方案。
Yeah.
嗯。
That's a good question,
这是个好问题，
I'm not actually sure, let me check.
我不太确定，让我检查一下。
[].
[]。
Sorry?
抱歉?
I'll type in the chat.
我会输入到聊天内容中。
Ha ha.
哈哈。